D.C. Public School Survey, Phase II Oral History Project OHP017
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
D.C. Public School Survey, Phase II Oral History Project
1998-1999
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Historical Society of Washington, D.C.
OHP017
1 Linear feet
2 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Transcripts Materials in this series include transcripts for all interviews. Series 2 Materials in this series include master copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are no duplicate copies of any audio recordings. There are no tapes for 19-09 and 19-17.
Biographical / Historical
Originally known as the Columbia Historical Society, the Historical Society of Washington, D.C. was founded in 1894. The society is an educational foundation and museum dedicated to preserving and displaying the history of the District, providing lectures, exhibits, classes, community events and other educational programs as part of its mission.
Custodial History
The Historical Society of Washington, D.C. conducted these interviews between 1998 and 1999. The transcripts of these interviews were transferred to the Library in the early 2000s. There is no deed of gift for this collection.
Scope and Contents
Between 1998 and 1999, the Historical Society of Washington, D.C. conducted a total of 40 oral history interviews with adults who had attended D.C. public schools. Topics include educational experiences, schools attended, and dates of graduation. The project director was Karen Washburn, Oral Historian for the Historical Society.
Oral History; Education; Neighborhoods; Childhood and youth
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts for all interviews.
  - Al Cruz, 1998 September 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stoff Smolson, 1998 September 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Webster, 1998 September 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dianne Dale and Gerald Boyd, 1998 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Austin Daindridge, 1998 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Doris Haynes, 1998 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lucille Johnson, 1998 September 20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ellen Nesheim, 1998 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Robert Silverman, 1998 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Trudy Standig, 1998 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Carter Bowman, 1998 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mamie Bowman, 1998 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Henry Brylawski. Molly Brylawski, Julien Brylawski, and Anita Summers Brylawski, 1998 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cynthia Jackson, 1998 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Nancy Pierce, 1998 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Charles Volkman, 1998 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - James Banks, 1998 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Carl Cole, 1998 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Lois Sinclair, 1998 October 26 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Nancy Suggs, 1998 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Thelma Baltimore, 1999 August 23 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Barbara Brooks, 1998 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Morris Butler, 1999 May 17 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bill Carnahan, 1999 March 26 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Charles Cassell, 1998 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Edna Juanita Jones Coleman, 1999 April 5 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Paul Phillips Cooke, 1999 July 7 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - John Davis, 1999 April 13 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Grace Ridgeley Drew, 1999 April 6 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Oliver Gasch, 1999 April 29 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Russell Gregory, 1999 March 29 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Austin Kiplinger, 1999 July 3 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Marian Reid, 1999 March 19 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Martha J. Roche, 1999 March 30 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Joseph Rogers, 1999 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Burke Syphax, 1999 July 28 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Series 2
  Materials in this series include master copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are no duplicate copies of any audio recordings. There are no tapes for 19-09 and 19-17.